哥伦比亚影业
出品
1462年
The year, 1462.
康斯坦丁堡陷落
Constantinople had fallen.
信奉回教的土耳其人  大军横扫欧洲
Moslem Turks swept into Europe with a vast, superior force...
痛击罗马尼亚  威胁整个基督教世界
...striking at Romania, threatening all of Christendom.
川索凡尼亚有一名圣龙会武士
From Transylvania arose a Romanian knight...
名叫德古拉
...of the Sacred Order of the Dragon, known as Dracula.
战役前夕
On the eve of the battle...
他挚爱的新娘
...his bride, Elisabeta...
伊莉莎白
...whom he prized above all things on Earth...
知道他将与强敌对阵
...knew that he must face an insurmountable force...
可能一去不返
...from which he might never return.
( 赞美主  我已获胜 )
God be praised. I am victorious.
伊莉莎白
Elisabeta.
诡诈的土耳其军射箭入城
The vengeful Turks shot an arrow into the castle...
散布德古拉阵亡的谣言
...carrying false news of Dracula's death.
伊莉莎白信以为真
Elisabeta, believing him dead...
投河自尽
...flung herself into the river.
我的王子死了
My prince is dead.
没有他生存毫无意义
All is lost without him.
但愿能在天堂重逢
May God unite us in heaven.
( 她是自尽死的 )
She has taken her own life.
( 她的灵魂不能升入天堂)
Her soul cannot be saved.
( 要受天谴)
She is damned.
( 这是神的律令 )
It is God's law.
( 这就是我捍卫教会的报偿吗 )
Is this my reward for defending God's church?
( 放肆 )
Sacrilege!
( 我唾弃上帝 )
I renounce God!
( 我将死后复生 )
I shall rise from my own death...
( 用尽邪恶力量为她复仇 )
...to avenge hers with all the powers of darkness.
( 血是生命泉源 )
The blood is the life...
( 我将饮血维生 )
...and it shall be mine!
片名: 吸 血 僵 尸 惊 情 四 百 年
伦敦  1897年
四个世纪后
卡费斯区精神病院
我都照你的吩咐做了  主人
I've done everything that you asked, master.
一切准备就绪
All the preparations are in order.
万事俱全
Everything.
我等待你的命令
I await your command.
因为
For I know...
当你论功行赏时
...that when the rewards are given...
你的慷慨会使我受益无穷
...I will be one of those who benefits from your generosity.
谢谢
Thank you.
伦费发狂了
Gone mad. Renfield is deranged.
心智丧失
He's lost his greedy mind, poor chap.
我想让你接手他的工作
I want you to take over for his foreign client...
替一个外国人德古拉伯爵理财
...this rather eccentric Count Dracula.
- 他要在伦敦近郊买房产  - 当然  先生
- He's buying up property in London. - Of course, sir.
我会转告伯爵  谢谢你的委派
I'll attend to the count. Thank you for your confidence.
这是你的大好良机  哈克
This is a great opportunity for you, Harker.
但你必须立刻前往川索凡尼亚
But you'll have to leave for Transylvania immediately.
终生难遇的机会
Opportunities such as this come but once in a lifetime.
那当然
Yes, of course, sir.
请问一下
If I may inquire...
伦费先生在川索凡尼亚怎么了
...what, in fact, happened to Mr. Renfield in Transylvania?
没什么
Nothing. Nothing.
私人问题
Personal problems.
完成这些交易
Close these transactions...
你在公司的前途无量
...and your future with this firm is assured.
是  我会全力以赴
Yes, sir. I will give it my full attention.
我们等了那么久
We've waited this long, haven't we?
我一回来就结婚
We can be married when I return.
好吧
Of course.
我会写信的
I'll write.
强纳生
Jonathan.
强纳生  我爱你
Jonathan, I love you.
我爱你  米娜
I love you, Mina.
5月25日  布达佩斯
25th May, Budapest.
今晨离开布达佩斯
Left Budapest early this morning.
依我看
The impression I had was that we were leaving the west...
这一带是罗马尼亚最东部
The district I am to enter is in the extreme east of the country...
三个州彼此相邻
...just on the borders of three states...
摩达维亚  布卡维纳及  川索凡尼亚
...Transylvania, Moldavia and Bukovina...
喀尔巴阡山交界处
...in the midst of the Carpathian Mountains...
欧洲最荒凉无名的一区
...one of the wildest and least known portions of Europe.
朋友
"My friend...
欢迎到喀尔巴阡山
...welcome to the Carpathians.
久候大驾多时
I am anxiously expecting you.
我的马车
At the Borgo Pass...
将在波戈隘口等你
...my carriage will await you and bring you to me.
深信你一路顺畅
I trust your journey from London has been a happy one...
并希望你在我国
...and that you will enjoy your stay...
身心愉快
...in my beautiful land.
你的朋友敬上  德
Your friend, D."
5月25日  日记
Diary, 25th May.
亲爱的强纳生离去近一周
My Jonathan has been gone almost a week.
我虽因不能立刻成婚感到失望
And although I was disappointed we could not marry before his departure...
仍为他出使重要任务而高兴
...I am happy that he got sent on this important assignment.
我渴望他的音讯
I am longing to hear all the news.
到外国一定很有趣
It must be so nice to see strange countries.
不知我和强纳生二人
I wonder if we-- I mean Jonathan and I...
能否一同出国游览
...shall ever see them together.
我们来早了  还没人来
We're early, driver. No one is here.
( 死人才走的快 )
For the dead travel fast.
城堡远不远
I say, is the castle far?
欢迎光临寒舍
Welcome to my home.
轻松自在地进来
Enter freely of your own will...
将你的欢乐留下
...and leave some of the happiness you bring.
德古拉伯爵
Count Dracula?
我正是
I am...
德古拉
...Dracula.
寒舍蓬壁生辉了  哈克先生
And I bid you welcome, Mr. Harker, to my house.
请进
Come in.
请恕我
You will, I trust, excuse me that I...
不奉陪
...do not join you.
我已经吃过了
But I have already dined.
而且我从不喝
And I never drink...
葡萄酒
...wine.
你的祖先吗  五官很像
An ancestor? I see a resemblance.
德古拉的徽记
The Order of the Dracul.
是条龙
The Dragon.
古代有个社团
An ancient society...
我的祖先宣誓入会
...pledging my forefathers...
保护教会抵御外侮
...to defend their church against all enemies of Christ.
结果却和教会
That relationship was not entirely...
闹僵
...successful.
是吗
Oh, yes.
这不是开玩笑的事
It is no laughing matter.
我们德古拉家族值得骄傲
We Draculs have a right to be proud.
不论阿提拉大帝如何残暴
What devil or witch was ever so great as Attila...
我也流着相同的血液
...whose blood flows in these veins?
血
Blood...
这年头成宝了
...is too precious a thing in these times.
杀伐的年代已过去
The warlike days are over.
我家族的光荣战迹
The victories of my great race...
只成为故事
...are but a tale to be told.
我是最后一名子嗣
I am the last of my kind.
恕我无知  伯爵
I have offended you with my ignorance, Count.
原谅我
Forgive me.
我渴望在伦敦拥挤的街道上
I do so long to go through the crowded streets...
漫步行走
...of your mighty London...
混在匆忙的人群中
...to be in the midst of the whirl and the rush of humanity...
分享它的生命力
...to share its life...
它的改变  及死亡
...its changes, its death.
完成了  伯爵
There. You, Count, are--
你是卡费教堂的所有人
Are the owner of Carfax Abbey at Purfleet.
恭喜
Congratulations.
贵公司对你
Your firm writes most highly...
赞许有加
...of your talents.
他们说你的品味
They say you are a man of good...
很高
...taste.
还说你能力不输给
And that you are a worthy substitute...
前任职员  伦费先生
...to your predecessor, Mr. Renfield.
你可以相信我
You may rely on me, Count.
恕我好奇
Forgive my curiosity, but why ten houses...
为何十所房子都买在伦敦附近
...in such precise locations around London?
炒地皮吗
Is it to raise the market value?
你相信宿命吗
Do you believe in destiny?
时间都可因
That even the powers of time...
某一目的而改变
...can be altered for a single purpose?
找到真爱的人
The luckiest man who walks on this Earth...
才是
...is the one who finds...
最幸运的人
...true love.
你找到米娜了
You found Mina.
我以为丢了呢
I thought she was lost.
我回去后就结婚
We're to be married as soon as I return.
你结婚了吗  伯爵
Are you married, Count?
先生
Sir...
你结婚了吗
...are you married?
结过一次
I was married once.
多年以前
Ages ago, it seems.
她死了
She died.
真令人难过
I'm very sorry.
是她命好
She was fortunate.
我一生凄凉
My life, at its best, is misery.
她一定会是个贤妻
She will no doubt make a devoted wife.
而你是个忠实的丈夫
And you a faithful husband.
来
Come.
写信给你公司
Write now, my friend, to your firm...
与心爱的人  说你要
...and to any loved ones, and say that it shall please you...
陪我住
...to stay with me...
一个月
...until a month from now.
A month?
你要我待那么久
Do you wish me to stay so long?
不可以拒绝
I will take no refusal.
1897年5月30日  日记
Diary, 30th of May, 1897.
强纳生不愿我在他出差时与露西同住
I know Jonathan does not want me to stay here with Lucy while he is away.
他怕我习惯威斯丁家的富贵后
He thinks that if I become accustomed to the wealth of the Westenra family...
便不肯当法律事务所职员的妻子
...I will not be content as the wife of a mere clerk in a law firm.
但我和露西自幼是好友
But Lucy and I have been friends since we were children...
她不在乎我只是个教师
...and she has never minded that I am only a schoolmistress.
好恶心
How disgustingly awful.
米娜
Mina!
一 千 零 一 夜
米娜
Mina.
米娜  你总在工作
Oh, Mina, you're always working.
你那有野心的强纳生
Is your ambitious Jon Harker...
逼你学打字
...forcing you to learn that ridiculous machine?
他也能逼你
When he could be forcing you to perform...
低级热情演出
...unspeakable acts of desperate passion on the parlor floor.
露西
Lucy, really.
你不该这样说我未婚夫
You shouldn't talk about my fiancé in such a way.
婚姻不只是肉体享乐
There's more to marriage than carnal pleasure.
是哦
Oh, Mina. So I see.
要多的多
Much, much more.
那是
That's--
这是什么  露西
What is it, Lucy?
我看不懂
Because I don't understand it.
男女真的
Can a man and woman really do...
这么做吗
...that?
我昨晚就做过
I did, only last night.
- 骗人  你没有  - 我有
- Fibber. You did not. - Yes, I did.
在我的梦里
Well, in my dreams.
强纳生有这么棒吧
Jonathan measures up, doesn't he?
你可以告诉我的
You can tell Lucy.
我们只接过吻
We've kissed. That's all.
他觉得娶不起我
He thinks he's too poor to marry me.
更糟的是我到你的华宅看你
And it's all the worse now that I'm here visiting you at Hillingham...
我的富有朋友
...my rich friend.
却没人向我求过婚
Yes, but not even one marriage proposal.
我快满20岁了
And here I am, almost 20...
是个老处女了
...practically a hag.
昆西·摩里斯先生到
Mr. Quincey P. Morris.
- 你看  - 那是什么人
- Oh, look. - What is that?
德州人
A Texan.
昆西·摩里斯
Quincey P. Morris.
他好年轻稚气
He's so young and fresh...
像我胯间的野种马
...like a wild stallion between my legs.
你真下流
You're positively indecent.
我只是知道男人想要什么
I just know what men desire.
看着
Watch.
- 昆西  亲爱的  - 露西小姐
- Quincey, darling. - Miss Lucy.
你像春雨般清新
Why, you're as fresh as the spring rain.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
昆西
Oh, Quincey.
求求你让我摸摸
Please let me touch it.
好大
It's so big.
小女孩
Little girl.
我亲爱的小女孩
Oh, my dear, sweet little girl.
我握着你的手
I hold your hand...
- 你也吻过我  - 杰克
- ...and you've kissed me. - Jack!
爱你深似海  小心
Oceans of love-- Oh, Jack, my darling.
我亲爱的小宝贝
Poor little baby.
小猫咪过来
My kitten, come over here.
来  吻一个就会好了
Come over here and I'll kiss it better.
我可怜的小花朵
My poor little blossom.
我可怜的小郎中  小医生
My poor little doctor. Brilliant doctor.
- 你好  昆西  - 杰克
- Hello, Quincey. - Jack.
坏熊  我摸摸爪子
What a naughty bear. Let me--
- 亚瑟·荷伍先生到  - 亚瑟
- Arthur Holmwood, Esquire. - Arthur!
亲爱的
Oh, my darling.
你气色真好
Oh, you look wonderful.
抱歉弄坏你的帽子
I'm so sorry about your hat.
- 好美  - 这是我的妖女装
- Charming. - It's my snake dress.
是吗
Is it really?
露西纯洁有德
Lucy is a pure and virtuous girl...
但她言语大胆真叫我震惊
...but I admit that her free way of speaking shocks me sometimes.
强纳生说
Jonathan says it is a defect of the aristocracy...
贵族都是口无遮拦
...that they say what they please.
但我崇拜露西
The truth is that I admire Lucy.
难怪男人爱她
I'm not surprised that men flock around her.
我希望我像她一样漂亮迷人
I wish I were as pretty and as adored as she.
他是怎样的人
What manner of man is this?
亚伦费
R.M. Renfield, successful solicitor...
霍汤公司得力干部
...in the firm of Hawkins and Thompkins...
法律俱乐部受人尊敬的会员
...respected member of the Lord Nugent's Windem Club...
从川索凡尼亚出差回来
...returns from business abroad in Transylvania...
精神完全崩溃
...promptly suffers a complete mental breakdown.
他现在嗜血如命
He's now obsessed with some blood lust.
乔治
George.
等着
Wait here.
吃开胃菜  西渥先生
Would you care for an hors d'oeuvre, Dr. Seward...
还是点心
...or a canapé?
不了  谢谢  伦费先生
No, thank you, Mr. Renfield.
今晚感觉如何
How are you feeling tonight?
比你好  单相思医生
Far better than you, my lovesick doctor.
你对我的私生活感兴趣吗
Is my personal life of interest to you?
当然  我对所有人都感兴趣
Of course it is. All life interests me.
你的食物  伦费先生  真恶心
Your diet, Mr. Renfield, is disgusting.
实际上很营养
Actually, they're perfectly nutritious.
我所摄取的生命
You see, each life that I ingest...
会带给我生命
...gives back life to me.
苍蝇带给你生命
A fly gives you life?
没错
Certainly.
叫我吃一般食物
But you might as well ask a man to eat molecules with a pair of chopsticks...
比用筷子夹分子还难
...than to interest me in a lesser carnivore.
我要为你发明疯子新分类法
I shall have to invent a new classification of lunatic for you.
蜘蛛你吃吗  蜘蛛吃苍蝇
What about spiders? Spiders eat the flies.
是的  蜘蛛吃苍蝇
Yes, spiders eat them.
麻雀你吃吗
What about sparrows?
吃  你刚才说麻雀吗
Oh, yes. Did you say sparrows?
- 体型大点的  - 对
- Something larger, perhaps? - Oh, yes.
小猫
A kitten.
求求你
I beg you.
一只受教爱玩
A little, sleek-- A playful kitten.
可喂食的小猫咪
Something I can teach. Something I can feed.
小猫咪而已嘛
No one would refuse me a kitten.
成年猫咪好吗
Wouldn't you prefer a cat?
好
Oh, yes.
一只大猫
A big cat.
- 我的救赎全靠它了  - 你的救赎
- My salvation depends upon it! - Your salvation?
没错  我需要生物
Yes. I need lives.
- 我需要生物  好献给主人  - 什么主人
- I need lives for the master. - What master?
主人即将抵达
The master will come...
他答应要让我不朽
...and he has promised to make me immortal.
用什么方法
How?
制服他
Get him off!
血便是生命
The blood is the life!
5月30日  德古拉城堡
30th May, Castle Dracula.
我发现怪异难言的事
I think strange things which I dare not confess to my own soul.
伯爵
The count...
看米娜照片的神情  让我害怕
...the way he looked at Mina's picture fills me with dread...
我仿佛置身在谜团中
...as if I have a part to play in a story that is not known to me.
我没听到你进来
I didn't hear you come in.
小心割到
Take care how you cut yourself.
刀子比你想象的危险
It is more dangerous than you think.
人类虚荣造出的邪恶东西
A foul bauble of man's vanity.
也许你可以
Perhaps you should...
蓄须
...grow a beard.
我要你写的信
The letters I requested.
写了吗
Have you written them?
很好
Good.
你若离开这几间房间
Should you leave these rooms...
劝你切勿
...you will not, by any chance...
到堡内其他区域过夜
...go to sleep in any other part of the castle.
古堡内
It is old...
有许多可怕的回忆
...and has many bad memories.
- 我警告过你了  - 我充分了解
- Be warned. - I'm sure I understand.
不要相信这种小玩意
Do not put your faith in such trinkets of deceit.
我们在川索凡尼亚
We are in Transylvania.
而川索凡尼亚不同于英国
Transylvania is not England.
我们的风俗习惯与你们不同
Our ways are not your ways.
你一定会
And to you...
觉得很怪异
...there shall be many strange things.
我已经看到许多怪事
I've seen many strange things already.
狼群追逐我穿过蓝色炼狱
Bloody wolves chasing me through some blue inferno!
你听听
Listen to them.
夜童的哭号
The children of the night.
多美妙的音乐
What sweet music they make.
音乐  那群野兽
Music? Those animals?
我照德古拉的意思写了三封信
I did as Dracula instructed. I wrote three letters.
给公司  家人及心爱的米娜
To the firm, to my family and to my beloved Mina.
我没提及我的恐惧
I said nothing of my fears as he will read them, no doubt.
因为我知道我成了囚犯
I know now that I am a prisoner.
强纳生
Jonathan.
强纳生  到我身边
Jonathan, come to me.
来
Come.
躺下
Lay down.
躺在我怀里
Lay back into my arms.
躺下
Lay back, Jonathan.
( 你们干嘛 )
What are you doing?
( 滚开 )
Get off!
( 不准碰他  他是我的 )
How dare you touch him! He belongs to me!
( 你从没恋爱过 )
You yourself never loved.
( 有  我能恋爱 )
Yes. I too can love.
( 而且我将再次恋爱 )
And I shall love again.
( 那我们今晚没血喝了吗 )
Are we to have nothing tonight?
葳荷米娜·墨瑞  希灵汉庄园
吾爱米娜  一切均安
"Dearest Mina, all is well here.
伯爵要我住一个月
The count has insisted I remain for a month...
教他英国礼俗
...to tutor him in English custom.
别无他语  只有我爱你
I can say no more, except I love you.
忠实至终的强纳生  呈上
Ever faithful, Jonathan."
这些信让我陷入绝境
The letters I have written have undoubtedly sealed my doom.
伯爵的吉普赛人  是英勇战士们
The count's gypsies, fearless warriors who are loyal to the death...
效忠这位贵族  死而无惧
...to whatever nobleman they serve...
他们日夜工作
...day and night they toil, filling boxes with decrepit earth...
将城堡的土装箱
...from the bowels of the castle.
运到刚购入的伦敦卡费教堂
They are to be delivered to his newly acquired Carfax Abbey in London.
为什么要装土呢
Why do they fill these boxes with earth?
我爱他  我爱他
I love him! I love him!
米娜
Oh, Mina!
妙不可言  我决定了
It's so wonderful. I've decided.
我爱他  我要嫁给他
I love him and I've said yes.
总算来了  你先别说  是带大刀的德州人吗
Finally. Don't tell me. The Texan with the big knife?
不  我要嫁第三号
Oh, no. To my dear number three.
亚瑟荷伍爵爷  荷伍勋爵夫妇
Lord Arthur Holmwood. Lord and Lady Holmwood.
你做伴娘  答应吧
You are to be my maid of honor. Oh, say yes.
怎么回事  今天是我大喜
Mina, what is it? It's the most exciting day of my life.
你好像漠不关心
You don't seem to care.
我只是很担心强纳生
It's just that I'm so terribly worried about Jonathan.
来信语气冷漠
This letter I received is so--
很不寻常  根本不像他
It's so cold. It's so unnatural. It's not like him at all.
别担心
Mina, don't worry.
丰饶女神号  船长日志
Captain's log: the Demeter.
1897年6月27日
27th June, 1897.
我们载了50箱实验用土
We picked up 50 boxes of experimental earth...
前往英国伦敦
...bound for London, England.
一场莫名风暴来袭
Set sail at noon into a storm...
恣意肆虐
...that seemed to come out of nowhere...
将我们推向汪洋
...carrying us out to sea.
伦敦动物园
7月3日  第二名船员失踪
Third of July. Second mate has gone missing.
接近直布罗陀海峡  风暴持续肆虐  船员非常不安
Nearing Gibraltar. Storm continues. Crew uneasy.
他们相信
Believe someone or something...
船上有鬼魅
...is aboard the ship with us.
伦敦
万物之主即将来到
The master of all life is at hand!
来了
Gather round!
我听候差遣  主人
I am here to do your bidding, master!
我已遥遥尊奉你许久
I have worshiped you long and far off!
如今你来了  主人
And now you are near, master!
我是你的奴隶
I am your slave!
我等候你的命令
I await your command!
伦费这病人愈来愈有趣
The case of Renfield grows more interesting.
他自有一套想法  他吃苍蝇  蜘蛛
Yet, there is method in his madness with his flies and spiders.
我若能解开疯人心智之谜
Had I the secret of even one such brilliant mind...
那该有多好
...the key to the fancy of one lunatic....
露西
Lucy.
Lucy?
露西
Lucy!
Lucy.
露西
Lucy!
不  不要看我
No. Do not see me.
露西  露西
Lucy! Lucy!
我控制不了自己
Oh! I couldn't control myself.
你在做梦  又梦游了
Hush, Lucy. You're dreaming. You're walking in your sleep again.
我的灵魂  出窍了
My soul, it seemed to leave my body.
我从没有如此痛苦的感觉  好像魂魄唤不回
There was this agonizing feeling, and I couldn't get back to it.
一直发抖
I'm absolutely shaking.
不要紧  做梦罢了
It's all right. You were dreaming.
狼人诱惑我
I had to. It sort of pulled me and lured me.
- 我禁不住  - 没事的
- I had no control. - It's all right.
- 它双眼血红  - 嘘了
- It had red eyes. - Hush now.
我还尝过它的血
I still have the taste of his blood in my mouth.
伦敦
山姆·毕林父子地产公司
箱子搬过来
Here we go. Swing it round here.
主人
Master.
我听候吩咐
I am here to do your bidding.
主人  我在这
Master! I am here!
我膜拜你
I have worshiped you.
与传说相反  吸血鬼
Contrary to some beliefs, the vampire...
如同夜行动物  白天亦可行动
...like any other night creature, can move about by day...
但因与其作息时间不同  法力也会因而衰退
...though it is not his natural time, and his powers are weak.
动物园的狼只逃出
史上最怪异的风暴
帆船船员神秘失踪
好棒的戏院
See the amazing cinematograph!
现代文明的奇能
A wonder of modern civilization!
最新奇观
The latest sensation!
最伟大的壮举
The greatest attraction of the century!
全球新奇观
The new wonder of the world!
快来戏院哦
See the zmazing cinematograph!
看我
See me.
看着我
See me now.
最强烈的突起暴风袭击英国
Record storm in London!
动物园逃出之狼仍未捕获
Escaped wolf from zoo still at large!
买份报纸吧  先生
Buy a paper, sir?
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
买报纸哦  买报纸
Get your Gazette! Penny a paper!
我最深的歉意
My humblest apologies.
恕我无知
Forgive my ignorance.
我刚上岸
I am recently arrived from abroad...
对贵地一无所知
...and I do not know your city.
- 美女是否可以  - 地图一份六便士  日安
- Is a beautiful lady-- - A street atlas is sixpence. Good day.
我冒犯你了
I have offended you.
我想看电影
I am only looking for the cinematograph.
听说是文明奇观
I understand it is a wonder of the civilized world.
要寻找文化就去博物馆
If you seek culture, then visit a museum.
伦敦有好几个  失陪
London is filled with them. Excuse me.
利辛戏院  哈姆雷特
如此美丽聪慧的女子
A woman so lovely and intelligent...
怎能在伦敦街头踽踽独行
...should not be walking the streets of London without her gentleman.
我认识你吗
Do I know you, sir?
你认识我丈夫吗
Are you acquainted with my husband?
我叫警察了
Shall I call the police?
丈夫
Husband?
不打扰了
I shall bother you no more.
先生
Sir.
我失礼了
It is I who have been rude.
- 若你找  - 求你了
- If you're looking-- - Please.
请容我自我介绍
Permit me to introduce myself.
我是罗马尼亚的弗拉王子
I am Prince Vlad of Sagite.
- 王子  真的吗  - 我
- A prince, no less? - I am...
听凭差遣
...your servant.
我叫葳荷米娜·墨瑞
Wilhelmina Murray.
我的
I am...
荣幸
...honored...
米娜小姐
...Madam Mina.
这边
This way.
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
晚上好
Good evening.
荷伍先生要我来看露西
Mr. Holmwood asked me to stop by to see Miss Lucy.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
- 西渥先生到  露西小姐  - 谢谢
- Dr. Seward, Miss Lucy. - Thank you.
杰克
Oh, Jack!
聪明的杰克  喜欢吗
Brilliant Jack. Do you like it?
亚瑟叫你来的吗
Did Arthur put you up to this...
还是你想在我婚前与我独处
...or did you want me alone just once before I'm married?
露西  你让我难为情
Lucy, you're embarrassing me.
我以医生身份来此
I'm here as your doctor.
你的未婚夫很担心你
Your fiancé is very worried about you...
医师的职责是神圣的
...and I assure you, a doctor's confidence is sacred.
我要你完全信任我
I must have your complete trust.
救我  杰克
Help me, Jack.
我不知怎么回事
I don't know what's happening to me.
我变了
I'm changing.
我可以感觉到
I can feel it.
我听觉灵敏
I can hear everything.
听得到仆人在房屋另一端私语
I hear the servants at the other end of the house, whispering.
阁楼的老鼠声大如象
I hear mice in the attic, stomping like elephants.
我一直做恶梦
But I'm having horrible nightmares, Jack.
那些眼睛
The eyes.
杰克
Oh, Jack.
有我在  露西  谁也伤不了你
I'm here, Lucy. Nothing will harm you.
药很有效
Let it work.
- 谢谢  - 露西
- Thank you. - Lucy.
杰克  吻我
Oh, Jack, kiss me.
露西小姐真骚
And may I say, Miss Lucy is hotter than a June bride...
她能裸体骑无鞍马
...riding bareback buck naked in the Sahara.
说话当心点
I would watch my colonial tongue if I were you.
你好  杰克  病人怎样了
Hello, Jack. And how's our lovely patient today?
老实说  我很惶惑
Well, frankly, Arthur, I'm confounded.
杰克  你还在替露西小姐担心吗
Jack, are you still brooding over Miss Lucy?
我看她是心智错乱
I can only conclude it must be something mental.
胡说  你听到没
How very droll. Did you hear that, Quince?
上周他要娶她  现在却要让她进疯人院
Last week he wanted to marry her, and now he wants to have her committed.
我们去瞧瞧她
Let's have a look at her.
我也不明白
I'm at a loss, I admit.
我已拍电报给亚伯汉·梵·海辛
I've taken the liberty of cabling Abraham Van Helsing...
精神哲学家
...the metaphysician, philosopher.
我看他是个巫医
Sounds like a goddamn witch doctor to me, Jack.
他是疑难杂症权威
Van Helsing knows more about obscure diseases than any man in the world.
也是我的良师
He's my teacher and mentor.
请他来  带他来此
Do it, man. Bring him here.
不论花多少钱
Spare no expense.
了不起
Astounding.
科学是无止尽的
There are no limits to science.
这哪叫科学
How can you call this science?
居礼夫人会同意这看法吗
Do you think Madam Curie would invite such comparisons?
说真的
Really.
我不该来的
I shouldn't have come here.
我得走了
I must go.
不要怕我
Do not fear me.
住手
Stop this.
天啊  你是谁
My God. Who are you?
我认识你
I know you.
我跨越时间的翰海
I have crossed oceans of time...
来寻你
...to find you.
各位来宾不要惊慌
There is no need to panic.
捕兽师自会处理
The animal handlers have everything under complete control.
过来  米娜
Come here, Mina.
他喜欢你
He likes you.
野兽能教导我们许多事
There is much to be learned from beasts.
好友濒死  不明原因之血疾
我急需协助  杰克·西渥
热带吸血蝙蝠
The tropical pampas vampire bat must...
一天要吸体重十倍的鲜血
...consume ten times its own weight in fresh blood each day...
否则它自己会死
...or its own blood cells will die.
小混球
Cute little vermin, ja?
我们研究血液及血液疾病
Blood and the diseases of the blood...
如梅毒
...such as syphilis, they concern us here.
性病  爱神之疾
The very name "venereal diseases"...
非常传神
...the diseases of Venus, imputes to them divine origin.
牵涉到基督文明
And they are involved in that sex problem about which...
对伦理与性的观念
...the ethics and ideals of Christian civilization are concerned.
其实  文明与梅毒几乎同步发展
In fact, civilization and syphilization have advanced together.
- 这是什么  - 电报
- What is this? - It's from the telegraph, Professor.
电报
Telegraph?
谢谢  谢谢各位  下课
Thank you. Gentlemen, thank you. That will be all.
黎明时刻
Dawn.
这也许是我最后一篇日记
These may be the last words I write in this journal.
德古拉把我丢给这些妖女
Dracula has left me with these women...
她们喝我的血
...these devils of the pit.
让我气息犹存
They drain my blood to keep me weak...
却逃不了
...barely alive so I cannot escape.
我今天尝试最后一次逃到水边
I will try one last time today to escape to the water.
一定有路可以通到河边
There must be passageway to the river...
逃出这受诅之地
...and then away from this cursed land...
及披着人皮的群魔
...where the devil and his children still walk with earthly feet.
我正式宣布
For the record, I do attest...
此刻亚拉汉·梵·海辛
that at this point, I, Abraham Van Helsing...
亲自调查这些怪事
...became personally involved in these strange events.
梵·海辛教授  你果然来了
Professor Van Helsing, how good of you to come.
我一向帮助需要我的朋友
I always come to my friends in need when they call me.
把病情详细告诉我
So, Jack, tell me everything about your case.
她有一般贫血症状
She has all the usual physical anemic signs.
血液分析正常
Her blood analyzes normal, and yet it is not.
但事实上她持续失血  我找不出原因
She manifests continued blood loss. I cannot trace the cause.
失血  怎么会
Blood loss? How?
把门关上
My God, close the doors!
天啊
My God...
她还是个孩子
...she's only a child.
对
Ja.
老天
My God.
不得延误  立刻输血
There's no time to lose. There must be a transfusion at once.
脱掉外套  还会绑止血带吧
Take off your coat. Remember how to tie a tourniquet?
- 或者你忘记了  - 你精通输血
- Or have you forgotten? - You perfected a procedure?
精通  不
Perfected? No. I've only experimented.
我只会蓝斯坦法
Landsteiner's method.
只替动物输过  山羊  绵羊啦
Animals, goats, sheeps.
若血清有溶血现像
If hemolysis occurs in the blood donor serum...
红血球会破裂
...her red blood cells will explode.
她就会死  把管子拿好
She will die. Take this tube.
你们在搞什么
What in God's name is going on up here?
这位是梵·海辛教授
This is Professor Van Helsing, Art.
- 他把露西怎么了  - 救她的命
- What the hell is he doing to Lucy? - He's trying to save her life.
- 老天  - 你是她的未婚夫  请让开
- Good God! - You're the fiancé? Please.
请让开
Please.
外套脱掉  她生命垂危
Take off your coat. This young lady's very ill. She's dying.
必须输血
She wants blood and blood she must have.
外套脱掉
Take off your coat.
袖子卷起来
Roll up your sleeve, Art.
- 老天  - 快
- Oh, God. - Quickly, quickly.
卷起来
Roll it up!
可能有点痛
This may hurt a little, Art.
请原谅我  先生
Forgive me, sir.
她是我的生命  把我最后一滴血给她都行
My life is hers. I would give my last drop of blood to save her.
最后一滴
Your last drop?
谢谢  欢迎你献身
Thank you. You are very welcome here.
我不要那么多  目前还不要
I don't ask as much as that. Not yet.
握住她的手
Hold her hand.
杰克  她输了两人份的血
Jack, that poor creature has had the blood of two men put into her already.
天啊  她装不了那么多血
Man alive. Her whole body couldn't hold that much blood.
- 露西的血去哪啦  - 问得好  摩里斯先生
- What took it out? - That's a good question, Mr. Morris.
喉咙那些痕迹
Those marks on her throat...
不是疾病或伤痕
...no disease, no trituration...
而是失血处
...I am sure the blood loss occurred there.
血去哪了呢
Oh? Where did the blood go?
你以前是个细心的学生  杰克
You were once a careful student, Jack.
用脑呀  血去哪啦
Use your brain! Where did the blood go?
告诉我
Tell me!
- 床铺上有血  - 没错
- The bed would be covered in blood. - Exactly.
你没观察到
You do not let your eyes see nor your ears hear...
不可知的现象
...that which you cannot account for.
有异物吸她的血后飞走了吗
Something just went up there, sucked it out of her and flew away?
有何不可
Ja. Why not?
高明  真高明
That's brilliant. That's absolutely brilliant.
神医  请问你
Will one of you learned doctors, or whatever you are...
露西究竟是怎么了
...kindly tell me what is going on with my Lucy?
杰克  你是个科学家
Jack, you are a scientist.
宇宙中可有你不明了的事实
Do you not think there are things in this universe you cannot understand...
例如催眠术
...and which are true. Mesmerism, hypnotism?
你和夏卡已证实了
You and Charcot have proved hypnotism.
实体与灵体
Materialization, astral bodies.
教授
Professor?
他去哪了
Where did he go?
看到了吧
You see?
我像是个菜鸟
I feel like a blundering novice.
我们对抗的不是疾病
Gentlemen, we're not fighting some disease here.
露西小姐的咬痕
Those marks on your dear Miss Lucy's neck were made...
是妖魔所致
...by something unspeakable out there.
已死又未死
Dead, but not dead.
妖魔追猎我们  原因不明
It stalks us for some dread purpose I do not comprehend.
它吸露西的血维持生命
To live, it feeds on Lucy's precious blood.
是个野兽  怪物
It is a beast, a monster.
我和露西是怎么了
What is happening to Lucy and to me?
年幼时我从不烦躁
When I was younger, my feelings were never troubled.
真希望能回复往日
I wish I were myself again...
那么敏锐  永可依赖的米娜
...the sensible Mina I always depended on.
艾伯森酒
Absinthe...
含春药的成分
...is the aphrodisiac of the self.
住在
The green fairy...
酒里的  绿仙子
...who lives in the absinthe...
要你的灵魂
...wants your soul.
但是
But...
你可以放心
...you are safe with me.
王子
Tell me, Prince...
告诉我你家乡的事
...tell me of your home.
全世界
The most beautiful place...
最美丽的地方
...in all creation.
一定是
Yes, it must be.
森林密布
A land beyond a great, vast forest...
山峦起伏
...surrounded by majestic mountains...
茂盛的葡萄园
...lush vineyards...
遍地开满无处可比拟的
...and flowers of such frailty and beauty...
妖艳花朵
...as to be found nowhere else.
你说的
You've described my home...
好像亲眼看过
...as if you had seen it firsthand.
或许受你的声调影响
It's your voice, perhaps.
好熟悉
It's so familiar.
仿佛
It's like--
梦中无法认出的声音
It's like a voice in a dream I cannot place...
在我孤独时
...and it comforts me.
- 安抚我  - 在你孤独时
- When I am alone. - When you are alone.
王妃呢
And what of the princess?
王妃
Princess?
有王子就有王妃
There is always a princess...
穿着白衣裙
...with gowns flowing white.
她的脸
And her face.
天啊
Oh, God...
她的脸
...her face...
是条河
...is a river.
王妃
The princess...
是条充满伤痛
...she's a river filled with tears of sadness...
心碎泪水的河
...and heartbreak.
是有过王妃
There was a princess.
伊莉莎白
Elisabeta.
她是全世界
She was the most radiant woman...
最耀眼的女子
...in all the empires of the world.
谣言拆散了她与王子
Man's deceit took her from her ancient prince.
她投入
She leapt to her death...
你提到的河而死
...into the river that you spoke of.
在我的母语中
In my mother's tongue...
那条河
...it is called...
被称作
...argesh.
王妃河
River princess.
亲爱的女士
Dear Madam.
安然无恙
...of the good sisters of the Blessed Sacrament.
哈克先生认为你有生命危险
Mr. Harker believes your life is in extreme danger...
他急切希望你到此
...and he desires with all urgency that you join him here...
立刻成婚
...so that you may immediately be married.
祝福你  阿格莎修女上
Yours with all blessings, Sister Agatha.
亲爱的王子
My sweet prince.
绝不能让强纳生知道
Jonathan must never know of us.
露西  露西
Lucy? Lucy.
我是亚拉汉·梵·海辛
Abraham Van Helsing
梵·海辛博士
Dr. Van Helsing.
你是米娜小姐  露西的好友
And you're Madam Mina, dear friend to our Lucy, ja?
- 她怎样了  - 仍很虚弱
- How is she, doctor? - She's still very weak.
她告诉我  你很担心
She tells me of your beloved Jonathan Harker...
你爱的强纳生
...and your worry for him.
我为所有的年轻爱侣担心
Well, I, too, worry for all young lovers.
生命中有黑暗
There are darknesses in life, my child...
也有光明
...and there are lights.
你便是光明  亲爱的米娜
You are one of the lights, dear Mina...
光明中的光明
...the light of all light.
去看你的朋友吧
Go now. See your friend.
米娜
Mina.
你不太一样  米娜
You look different, Mina.
脸上发光
You look positively radiant.
有强纳生的消息
You heard from Jonathan.
- 对吧  - 是的
- Didn't you? - Yes.
他平安无事  露西
He's safe, Lucy.
他在罗马尼亚一家修道院
He's in a convent in Romania.
得了严重的脑热病
He's suffering from a violent brain fever.
修女替他写信
The good sisters are caring for him.
说他需要我
They wrote to me, and they say he needs me...
但  我不去
...but I won't go.
我不要丢下你
I'm not going to leave you.
米娜
Mina.
你必须去
You've got to go to him...
你要爱他
...and you've got to love him...
立刻嫁给他
...and marry him right then and there.
这个你收下
And I want you to take this, my sister.
我送你的贺礼
It's my wedding gift to you.
不  露西
No, Lucy. No.
别担心任性的小露西
Don't worry about spoiled little Lucy.
我会康复的
I'll be all right.
代我向强纳生致爱
Tell Jonathan oceans of love.
她怎么了
Jack, how is she?
我受不了大蒜味
This is why I cannot breathe!
露西  这是药
Lucy, it's medicinal.
有助于你的睡眠
To help you sleep. To dream better dreams.
只是普通大蒜嘛
It's garlic! It's nothing but common garlic!
昆西来看你了  拿点白兰地来
Quincey's here to see you. Get some brandy.
露西小姐  你好好休息
Now, Miss Lucy, you just rest easy.
亚瑟叫我来看你
Arthur sent me to take care of you.
他说  如果你不尽快康复
He said if you don't get better quick...
我就得一枪毙了你  像对跛脚马般
...I have to put you out of your misery like a lame horse.
你真野蛮
You're such a beast.
吻我好吗  昆西
Will you kiss me, Quincey?
吻我
Kiss me.
- 老笨蛋  - 放开我
- That old coot! - Get off me!
听话  睡觉  立刻睡着
Listen to me! Sleep, sleep now. Sleep.
镇静
You're at peace.
你们看
Look. There. There.
诺斯费拉图  吸血鬼
Nosferatu.
吸 血 鬼
此篇讲述野蛮的
"Here occurs the shocking and frightening history...
德古拉王子骇人野史
...of the wild, berserk Prince Dracula.
他将人插住
How he impaled people and roasted them...
烤身  煮头
...boiled their heads in a kettle...
活生生的剥皮
...how he skinned them alive...
凌迟  饮他们的血
...and hacked them to pieces and then drank their blood."
德古拉
Dracul.
她的血便是生命
For blood is the life.
亲爱的王子  请原谅我
"My dearest Prince, forgive me.
我收到未婚夫自罗马尼亚的信
I have received word from my fiancé in Romania.
我要去见他并完婚
I am en route to join him. We are to be married.
永不再见
I will never see you again.
米娜
Mina."
奇怪
It is odd, but I feel almost...
那位怪友好像也跟来了
...that my strange friend is with me.
他在我的思绪中
He speaks to me in my thoughts.
与他在一起  我最有活力
With him I felt more alive than ever I had.
如今他不在  又将成婚
And now without him, soon to be a bride...
我深感困惑失落
...I feel confused and lost.
也许我虽想做好  其实很坏
Perhaps, though I try to be good, I am bad.
或许我是个善变的坏女人
Perhaps I am a bad, inconstant woman.
台风
Winds!
刮大风吧
就是这原因
It is the cause.
就是它
It is the cause of my soul!
天啊  德古拉
It is Dracula...
这个僵尸
...the undead...
我一生追击的敌人
...the foe I have pursued all my life.
德古拉
Dracula!
杰克  快  有好多事要告诉你
Jack, hurry! I have much to tell you.
小心守候
Guard her well, Mr. Morris.
今晚不得失误
Do not fail here tonight.
我们对抗的是
We are dealing with forces beyond all human experience...
超越凡人的法力
...an enormous power, so guard her well.
否则你的露西会变成女妖
Otherwise your precious Lucy will become a bitch of the devil...
邪恶的魔女
...a whore of darkness!
老疯子
You're a sick old buzzard.
听清楚  小子
Hear me out, young man.
露西不是意外所致
Lucy is not a random victim attacked by mere accident.
明白吗
Do you understand? No.
她自愿受其蛊惑
She is a willing recruit, a breathless, wanton follower.
忠实的门徒
I dare say, a devoted disciple.
她是魔鬼的姘妇
She is the devil's concubine!
懂了吗
Do you understand me?
但我们仍可救回她的灵魂
Yet, we may still save her precious soul.
不过得先填饱肚子
But not on an empty stomach.
- 杰克  - 是的
- Jack! - Here, sir.
我饿死了  快跟我去吃饭
I starve. Feed me.
老傻子
You old coot!
无能的人类  跟愚蠢的驱邪物
Your impotent men with their foolish spells...
保护不了你
...cannot protect you from my power.
我诅咒你成为僵尸
I condemn you to living death...
永远
...to eternal hunger...
嗜饮鲜血
...for living blood.
杰克
Jack.
我知道你深爱她  所以你得相信我
I know how deeply you loved her. That is why you must trust me and believe.
教我如何相信
Believe? How can I believe?
你在天黑前带解剖刀来
I want you to bring me, before nightfall, a set of postmortem knives.
解剖  露西
An autopsy? Lucy?
不完全是  我要割她的头  挖她的心
No, not exactly. I just want to cut off her head and take out her heart.
9月17日  日记
Diary, 17th September.
可怜的强纳生  他仍重病
Poor Jonathan. He's still so ill.
但回到伦敦他很开心
He's cheered by the familiar streets in London.
而我  因露西已死反而难过
For me, now that Lucy is dead, it is a sad homecoming.
仿佛部分的我也已死去
It is as if a part of me is dead too...
除了暗盼
...except for the tiny hope that lives in me...
能再见到我的王子
...that I will again see my prince.
他在伦敦吗
Is he here?
我已结婚
Now that I am married...
现在才明白  对萦绕心中的他
...I begin to understand the nature of my feelings for my strange friend...
是怎样的情绪
...who is always in my thoughts.
强纳生  怎么了
Jonathan, what is it?
就是他
It is the man himself.
他变年轻了
Look, he's grown young.
各位  非掘露西的墓吗
Gentlemen, must we desecrate poor Lucy's grave?
她死的够惨了
She died horribly enough.
若她已死则无碍
If Miss Lucy is dead, then no wrong can be done to her.
若没死
But if she's not dead....
你是说她被活埋了吗
What are you saying, man? That she's been buried alive?
不  我只是说  她没死
No. All I say is she is undead.
没死
Undead.
疯狂
This is insane.
各位  动手吧
Gentlemen, shall we?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
她呢
Where is she?
你把她怎么了
What have you done with her?
她住在上帝恩典不及之处
She lives beyond the grace of God...
飘荡在黑暗界
...a wanderer in the outer darkness.
她是吸血鬼
She is vampyre, nosferatu.
这些怪物被吸血后不会死
These creatures do not die like the bee after the first sting...
反受传染
...but instead grow strong and become immortal...
而成不朽
...once infected by another nosferatu.
所以  吾友  我们不是对抗一个怪物
So my friends, we fight not one beast...
而是长久流传于世的
...but legions that go on age after age after age...
以血为生的族群
...feeding on the blood of the living.
快躲起来
Quickly, hide. Now.
露西
Lucy.
来  亚瑟
Come to me, Arthur.
扔下其它人  来我这里
Leave these others and come to me.
我好想拥抱你
My arms are hungry for you, my darling.
吻我  抱我
Kiss me and caress me...
我亲爱的丈夫  我求你
...my darling husband, please.
我们有十字架和圣水
We wave Christ and His holy blood!
主赋予我们力量  主赋予我们力量
We are strong in the Lord and the power of His might!
我们在主内坚强
The power of God is upon us!
我将你带至光明
I bring you from shadow into light!
黑暗王子  我将你
I cast you out, the prince of darkness...
逐至地狱
...into hell!
只需片刻勇气
A moment's courage, and it is done.
左手拿凿子
Take the stake in your left hand...
对准心脏
...place the point over the heart.
奉主之名  敲下去
Then in God's name, strike. Do it now!
吃呀  大餐  将来你们需要力气
Eat, feast. You'll need your strength for the dark days ahead.
米娜
Mina.
- 博士  - 嗯
- Doctor? - Ja?
露西怎么死的
How did Lucy die?
嗯
Well--
她死前痛苦吗
Was she in great pain?
是的  我们砍掉了她的头
Ja, she was in great pain. Then we cut off her head...
在心脏钉下十字架  她就安息了
...drove a stake through her heart and burned it and then she found peace.
博士  拜托别说了
Doctor! Please.
哈克先生
So, Mr. Harker...
身为你的医生  问你个
...I must now ask you, as your doctor...
敏感问题
...a sensitive question.
你和那些怪物在一起时
During your infidelity with those creatures...
那些妖女
...those demonic women...
你可曾吃过  她们的血
...did you, for one instant, taste of their blood?
没有
No.
No?
没有
No.
很好
Good!
那你没染上
Then you have not infected your blood with the terrible...
露西那种病
...disease that destroyed poor Lucy.
博士  你要知道
Doctor, you must understand.
以前我疑幻似真
I doubted everything...
甚至以为自己疯了
...even my mind.
终日恐惧
I was impotent with fear.
- 我知道  - 但是
- I know. - But, sir...
我知道吸血鬼睡在哪
...I know where the bastard sleeps.
我把他带到  卡费教堂
I brought him there, to Carfax Abbey.
吸血鬼的确存在
Vampires do exist.
我们围攻的这一个
And this one we fight, this one we face...
有二十人的力气
...has the strength of 20 or more people...
你可以证明
...and you can testify for that, Mr. Harker.
他能控制低等的动物
But he can also control the meaner things of life...
蝙蝠  老鼠  野狼
...the bat, the rodent, the wolf.
他还能化为烟雾遁形
He can appear as mist, as vapor, as fog and vanish at will.
德古拉法力是大
Now, all these things Dracula can do...
但他不自由
...but he is not free.
他必须躺在故土中增加魔力
He must rest in the sacred earth of his homeland to gain his evil power.
我们必须在此将他毁灭
It is here that we must find him and destroy him utterly.
我替这个伯爵难过
I almost feel pity for anything so hunted as this count.
你怎会怜悯这种怪物
How can you pity such a creature?
我带米娜到我医院
I'll take Mina to my quarters.
你在那儿才安全
Good. You'll be safer there.
子弹伤不了他  一定得砍头
Mr. Morris, your bullets will not harm him.
我建议你用猎刀
He must be beheaded. I suggest you use your big bowie knife.
我不打算贴近他  博士
Well, I wasn't planning on getting that close, Doc.
主人
Master!
杰克大夫
Dr. Jack!
我获准得永生
I've been promised eternal life!
杰克  那人是谁
Dr. Seward, who is that man?
那是伦费先生  你不适合久留
Mr. Renfield. This is no place for you, Madam Mina.
伦费  我得见他
Renfield? I must see him.
伦费先生  别乱来
Mr. Renfield, behave yourself.
这位是哈克太太
This is Mrs. Harker.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好 伦费先生
- Good evening. - Good evening, Mr. Renfield.
我太调皮了
It seems I've been rather naughty.
我认识你
I know you.
你是主人的新娘
You're the bride my master covets.
我有丈夫了
I have a husband.
我是哈克太太
I am Mrs. Harker.
我的主人提过你
My master tells me about you.
他怎么说
What does he tell you?
说他要来
That he is coming.
他要来找你
That he is coming for you.
过来点
Oh, please.
别留在这
Don't stay here.
离开那些人  求求你
Get away from these men, please.
我祈求主不要再见到你
And I pray to God I may never see your sweet face again.
愿主祝福保佑你
And may the Lord bless and keep you.
主人  主人
Master! Master!
你答应我让我永生的
You promised me eternal life...
你却给了这名美女
...but you give it to the pretty woman!
杰克大夫
Dr. Jack!
我不是疯子
I'm no lunatic man!
我很正常  在为灵魂奋战
I'm a sane man fighting for his soul!
我的房间很简陋  但很舒适
My quarters are spare, but I think you will find them comfortable.
杰克大夫
Dr. Jack!
有水和清洁用品
Water and toiletries at your disposal.
你在这十分安全
You'll be completely safe here.
毁掉每个箱子  浇圣水
Destroy every box. Sterilize the earth inside.
让他无处可逃
Leave him no refuge.
开始驱魔
Let the exorcism begin.
伦费
Renfield.
你背叛了我
You have betrayed me.
没有
No.
不  主人
No, master.
我没有
No, I--
我侍奉你
I serve you.
我只侍奉你
I serve only you.
吾爱
Oh, yes, my love.
你找到我了
You've found me.
我最珍贵的生命
My most precious life.
我要这事发生
I have wanted this to happen.
我都知道了
I know that now.
我要永远和你在一起
I want to be with you always.
你不明白自己在说什么
You cannot know what you are saying.
我知道
Yes...
我明白
...I do know.
我怕再也感受不到你的触摸
I feared I would never feel your touch again.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
这幅躯壳里没有生命
There is no life in this body.
但你活着
But you live.
你是活的
You live.
你到底是什么
What are you?
我要知道  你一定得告诉我
I must know. You must tell me.
我
I am...
什么都不是
...nothing.
没有生命
Lifeless.
- 没有灵魂  - 什么意思
- Soulless. - What do you mean?
人皆恨我怕我
Hated and feared.
我在世上已死
I am dead to all the world.
听好
Hear me.
我是
I am the monster...
众人皆欲杀之的怪物
...that breathing men would kill.
我就是德古拉
I am Dracula.
你杀死了露西
You murdered Lucy!
天啊
God.
我爱你
I love you.
上帝啊  原谅我  我爱你
Oh, God, forgive me, I do.
我要变得和你一样
I want to be what you are...
见你所见
...see what you see...
爱你所爱
...love what you love.
米娜
Mina.
想和我一样
To walk with me...
你必须死亡
...you must die to your breathing life...
在我的世界重生
...and be reborn to mine.
你永远是我的爱
You are my love...
与生命
...and my life always.
那么
Then...
我将让你永生
...I give you life eternal...
给你长久不息的爱
...everlasting love...
教你  呼风唤雨
...the power of the storm...
降兽驯禽
...and the beasts of the earth.
跟我走
Walk with me...
永远  为我爱妻
...to be my loving wife forever.
我愿意
I will. Yes. Yes.
喝下去  同我迈入
Drink and join me...
永生
...in eternal life.
不  我不能害你
I cannot let this be.
我不在乎  占有我吧
Please, I don't care. Make me yours.
米娜  你将让我永世
You will be cursed as I am to walk in the shadow of death...
被诅咒
....for all eternity.
我太爱你
I love you too much...
而不能害你
...to condemn you.
带我远离死亡阴影
Then take me away from all this death.
米娜
Mina.
你以为十字架
You think you can destroy me...
可以杀死我
...with your idols?
拿圣水
Sacred blood of Christ!
我服侍十字架
I, who served the cross.
在数百年前
I, who commanded nations...
我曾领导万军
...hundreds of years before you were born.
你的军队溃败
Your armies were defeated.
你折磨刑囚千万人
You tortured and impaled thousands of people.
我被背弃
I was betrayed.
看  你的上帝
Look what your God...
如何对待我
...has done to me.
你与上帝的战争已结束  伏法吧
No, your war with God is over. You must pay for your crimes.
基督制伏你
Christ compels you!
现在
She is now...
她是我的新娘了
...my bride!
灯火
More light!
灯火  不够
Light! More light!
好脏啊
Unclean.
- 捉住那些老鼠  - 这边
- Get them! - This way!
- 得烧掉  - 他们一定会被发现的
- Get them! - They must be found.
不洁净
Unclean.
我们学到很多
We have learned something much.
德古拉怕我们  他怕时间
Dracula fears us. He fears time.
否则何必匆匆逃走
For, if not, why does he hurry so?
他走了
He is gone.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
他告诉我的
He speaks to me.
他和你心灵相通
He has a strong mind connection to you.
他的心脏强壮  熬的住死亡
His heart was strong enough to survive the grave.
- 你赞赏他  - 嗯
- You admire him. - Ja.
他生前是个伟人
He was, in life, a most remarkable man...
思虑恢宏
...and his mind was great and powerful...
但更重要的是
...but greater is the necessity to stamp him out...
让他永不超生
...and destroy him utterly.
- 博士  - 嗯
- Doctor? - Ja?
我知道我愈来愈像他
I know that I am becoming like him.
你的救赎是他的毁灭
Your salvation is his destruction.
所以我要催眠你
That is why I want to hypnotize you.
我要你及时
I want you to help me find him before it is too late.
助我找到他  请帮我找到他
Please, help me find him. Please.
看这烛光
Look into this light...
光明中的光明
...the light of all light, into this flame.
你双眼沉重
Your eyes are heavy.
你想睡觉  睡吧
You want to sleep. Sleep now.
- 睡吧  - 我要去找他
- Sleep. - I must go to him.
他在叫我
He calls.
你听到了什么
What do you hear?
听到了什么
What do you hear, child?
What do you hear?
我的王子在呼唤我
Oh, my prince is calling me.
他飘洋过海
He is traveling across icy seas to his beloved home.
回家滋长力量
There he will grow strong again.
我要去找他  分享他的力量
I am coming to him to partake of his strength.
我们当晚在波涛中航过英吉利海峡
We left London by train and crossed the English Channel in stormy seas...
风浪无疑是伯爵的杰作
...no doubt from the passage of the count's ship.
他呼风唤雨  但我们仍占上风
He commands the winds, but we still have the advantage.
搭火车三天内可抵达瓦纳
By train, we can reach the Romanian port at Varna in three days.
搭船至少要一周
By ship, it will take him at least a week.
从巴黎经阿尔卑斯至布达佩斯
From Paris, we traveled through the Alps to Budapest.
伯爵一定得经过直布罗陀
The count must sail around the Rock of Gibraltar...
我们已派人看守
...where we have posted a lookout...
至黑海瓦纳港
...and then on to the Black Sea port in Varna...
我们在瓦纳与他碰头  将船烧毁
...where we will meet his ship and burn it into the sea.
回家
Home. Home.
吸血鬼以血为她受洗
The vampire's baptized her with his own blood...
她已成吸血鬼
...and her blood is dying, my friend.
没办法了
It is no use.
我不让你只身入险地
I will not let you go into the unknown alone.
可怜的强纳生
Oh, my poor, dear Jonathan.
我对不起你
Oh, what have I done to you?
不  是我害了我们俩
No, I have done this to both of us.
我听到他了  他接近了
I can hear him. He's coming closer.
他在呼唤我
He's calling me to him.
米娜  米娜
Mina. Mina.
留下来  求求你
Stay with me. Please.
我好冷
I am so cold.
上车
All aboard!
正午  荷伍接到公司的电报
Noon. Holmwood received a wire from his clerk at Lloyd's.
伯爵的船在夜雾中
The count's ship sailed past us in the night fog...
赶过我们
...to the northern port of Galatz.
这个魔鬼在探索米娜的思想
The black devil is reading Mina's mind.
怎么捉他
How can we catch him now?
瓦纳港  格拉兹
Varna. Galatz.
约两百英里
It's about 200 miles.
骑马可在他
I think that with the horses, we can cut him off...
抵达古堡前拦截他
...reach him before he reaches the castle.
我会派梵·海辛到波戈隘口
I will dispatch Van Helsing straight for the Borgo Pass.
若我们失败
If we fail in our task...
你一定得杀掉他
...you will have to finish him.
米娜和梵·海辛在瓦纳搭马车
From Varna, Mina and Van Helsing took a carriage...
我们朝格拉兹前进
...and we continued on the train towards Galatz...
希望能在他登陆前拦截到
...where we still hoped to intercept the count before he reaches land.
我为米娜害怕  她是诱饵
I am fearful for Mina. She is now our decoy.
我认得这地方
I know this place.
- 世界的尽头  - 我们得继续走
- The end of the world. - We must go on.
天晚了  休息吧
It is late, child. We must rest here now.
我们得走
No, we must go!
米娜
Mina.
他需要我  非得走
He needs me. We must go!
我们已通过毕斯屈栅
We have passed Bistritza.
德古拉又赢过我们
Dracula has outsmarted us again.
我们得知箱子在格拉兹被运走
We learned that his gypsies took charge of the vampire's box at Galatz...
已在波戈隘口的路上
...and are now on the Borgo Pass road.
- 你一定得吃  - 我不饿
- Here. You must eat. - I am not hungry.
米娜
Mina?
你对我很好  教授
You have been so good to me, Professor.
我知道露西暗恋你
I know that Lucy harbored secret desires for you.
她告诉我的
She told me.
我也知道男人要什么
I, too, know what men desire.
你会砍我头
Will you cut off my head...
用十字架穿我的心吗
...and drive a stake through my heart...
你这凶手
...as you did poor Lucy, you murdering bastard?
绝不会  我发誓要保护你
Not while I live. I am sworn to protect you.
不
No!
你在圈内很安全
You are safe within the circle.
我已输掉露西  不能再将你输给他
I've lost Lucy. I'll not lose you to him.
撤旦的臭婊子
You're whores of Satan!
这里是圣地
This is holy ground.
立刻走开
Leave this place now!
走
Leave!
奉主之名
In the name of God, leave this ground!
离开这块圣地
I command you in the name of Christ!
不
No!
主啊  该死
Christ! Damn you!
德古拉
Dracul!
米娜
Mina.
你就在
You are...
附近了
...near.
吾爱
My love.
他们要在日落前赶到
They're racing against the sunset.
也许已经来不及
It may be too late. God help us.
米娜
Mina.
开枪
Harker, shoot!
攻呀
Charge!
哈克
Harker!
不
No!
米娜
Mina!
昆西
Quincey!
不
No!
不要
当你要杀我时  你下得了手吗
When my time comes, will you do the same to me?
你会吗
Will you?
- 不  - 放他们走
- Wait. - Let them go.
我们的工作到此为止
Let them go. Our work is finished here.
她的工作才刚开始
Hers has just begun.
昆西
Quincey.
我们都成了上帝的疯子
We've all become God's madmen.
我们都是
All of us.
我的上帝呢
Where is my God?
他抛弃了我们
He has forsaken me.
结束了
It is finished.
不
No!
吾爱
My love.
在上帝面前
There, in the presence of God...
我终于了解
...I understood at last how my love could release us all...
我的爱让我们脱离黑暗魔咒
...from the powers of darkness.
我们的爱比死更强大
Our love is stronger than death.
让我安息
Give me peace.
导演
弗朗西斯·福特·科波拉
编剧
詹姆士·V·哈特
制片
弗朗西斯·福特·科波拉
弗莱德·福斯
查尔斯·穆尔维西尔
监制
迈克尔·艾普特
与
罗伯特·奥康纳
领衔主演
加里·奥德曼
薇诺娜·瑞德
安东尼·霍普金斯
基努·里维斯
理查德·E·格兰特
加利·艾尔维斯
比尔·坎贝尔
特别介绍
珊迪·弗罗斯特
以及
汤姆·威兹
扮演  伦费
摄影指导
迈克尔·巴尔豪斯
艺术指导
托马斯·桑德斯
剪辑
格伦·斯坎特伯里
安妮·格鲁莎德
尼古拉斯·C·史密斯
服装设计
石冈瑛子
原创音乐
沃伊切赫·基拉尔
视觉特效及第二组导演
罗曼·科波拉
选角
维多利亚·托马斯
联合制片
约翰·维奇
詹姆士·V·哈特
助理制片
苏西·兰道
美国西洋镜
奥西瑞斯影业
制片
"吸 血 鬼 情 歌"   演唱   安妮·蓝妮克丝
"Love Song for a Vampire" Single by Annie Lennox
♪ 当你的躯体倒下 ♪
♪ Come into these arms again ♪
♪ 重入我臂弯之中 ♪
♪ And lay your body down ♪
♪ 我心颤抖地律动 ♪
♪ The rhythm of this trembling heart ♪
♪ 有如鼓点隆隆 ♪
♪ Is beating like a drum ♪
♪ 它为你跳动  它因你跳动 ♪
♪ It beats for you, it bleeds for you ♪
♪ 传到你耳中却成了空 ♪
♪ It know not how it sound ♪
♪ 也许这只是鼓声杂乱 ♪
♪ For it is the drum of drums ♪
♪ 也许这只是歌声平凡 ♪
♪ It is the song of songs♪
♪ 我曾拥有珍奇的玫瑰 ♪
♪ Once I had rarest rose ♪
♪ 在它绽放之前 ♪
♪ That ever deigned to bloom ♪
♪ 残忍的寒冬便将它的蓓蕾冰冻 ♪
♪ Cruel winter chilled the bud ♪
♪ 一并窃走吾爱  迅如寒风 ♪
♪ And stole my flower too soon ♪
♪ 如此孤独  希望空洞 ♪
♪ Oh loneliness, oh hopelessness ♪
♪ 我渴望时间的末终 ♪
♪ To search the ends of time ♪
♪ 只因这世上 ♪
♪ For there is in all the world ♪
♪ 我伟大的爱情无人契同 ♪
♪ No greater love than mine ♪
♪ 爱  吾爱 ♪
♪ Love, oh love, oh love ♪
♪ 依旧伴着冷雨 ♪
♪ Still falls the rain (still falls the rain) ♪
♪ 爱  吾爱 ♪
♪ Love, oh love, oh, love ♪
♪ 依旧伴着黑夜 ♪
♪ Still falls the night ♪
♪ 爱  吾爱 ♪
♪ Love, oh love, oh love ♪
♪ 伴我永生 ♪
♪ Be mine forever (be mine forever) ♪
♪ 爱  吾爱 ♪
♪ Love, oh love, oh love ♪
♪ 让我成为你的唯一 ♪
♪ Let me be the only one ♪
♪ 拯救你远离寒冬 ♪
♪ To keep you from the cold ♪
♪ 现在  天堂之门已经敞开 ♪
♪ Now the floor of heaven's lain ♪
♪ 有金子般的群星围拱 ♪
♪ With stars of brightest gold ♪
♪ 它们为你耀动 ♪
♪ They shine for you, they shine for you ♪
♪ 它们让世人见证我们的爱火熊熊 ♪
♪ They burn for all to see ♪
♪ 回归我臂弯之中 ♪
♪ Come into these arms again ♪
♪ 从此  我们的灵魂自由从容 ♪
♪ And set this spirit free ♪
剧 终
THE END